worketc.com 2019-01-19

# Privacy Policy – we hate spam too. : WORKetc Business Management Software | CRM, Project Management, Billing

PRIVACY POLICY

Effective Date: May 25th 2018

To review material modifications and their effective dates scroll to the bottom of the page.

WORKETC PTY LTD (“WORKetc”) owns and operates this worketc.com website business. All references to “we”, “us”, this “website” or this “site” shall be construed to mean WORKetc. We understand that visitors to this website are concerned about the privacy of information. The following describes our privacy policy regarding information, including Personal Information, that we collect through this website. By using this website you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our website www.worketc.com and WORKetc service. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged WORKetc.

Together with our Customer Terms and any other documents referred within, this Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which any personally identifiable information (“Personal Data”) we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your Personal Data and how we will treat it in respect of your use of capsulecrm.com (“the Service”).

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at:

WORKetc Pty Ltd  
Attn: Privacy Policy Officer  
Level 8, 99 Elizabeth St  
SYDNEY NSW AUSTRALIA  
Email: support@worketc.com

THE TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Personal Information.  We collect Personal Information that you provide to us and that may be used to identify you (“Personal Information”).  Personal Information that we collect may vary with each separate purpose for which you provide it, and it may include one or more of the following categories: name, physical address, an email address, phone number, and credit card information including credit card number, expiration date, and billing address.

Non-Personal Information.  We reserve the right to collect anonymous information such as your browser type, the URL of the previous website you visited, your computer’s operating system and Internet protocol (IP) Address, Internet domain and host name, your Internet Service provider, your clickstream data, and the dates and times that you may access this site and specific pages (Non-Personal Information”).  Non-Personal Information is essentially anonymous when collected; however, it’s possible that Non-Personal Information could be used to identify you.

For EU domiciled Customers, or Customers with operation activities within the EU, a GDPR-compliant data flow map is available [by request](https://www.worketc.com/worketc-gdpr/#MAPDOC).

HOW AND WHEN WE COLLECT INFORMATION

Personal Information.  We collect Personal Information at the time you provide it to us.  We collect Personal Information through sign-up forms and as part of your registration for an account, product, or service from this website.  Personal information that we collect may vary with the each sign-up or registration.

Your Communications With Us.  We collect Personal Information that we receive from you as you communicate with us.

Passive and Analytical Information.  We reserve the right to monitor your use of this site.  As you navigate through this site, Non-Personal Information may be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various analytics and reporting technologies, such as cookies and web beacons.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We use your Personal Information for the performance of the services (such as payment processing and email communications) or transaction for which it was given, our private, internal reporting for this site, and security assessments for this site.

We do NOT tie or link your Personal Information to Non-Personal Information with persistent identifiers.  For example, we would not tie or link your email address (Personal Information) with information collected by a cookie regarding the length of time you visit our site (Non-Personal Information).

We reserve the right to make full use of Non-Personal Information.  For example, we may use Non-Personal Information to provide better service to site visitors, customize the site based on your preferences, compile and analyze statistics and trends about the use of this site, and otherwise administer and improve this site for your use.

HOW WE DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION

General Disclosure Policy.   Our general policy is that we will not share, sell, or rent your Personal Information to others.  The only exceptions to this general policy: (i) are described in the subsections below, and (ii) if you explicitly approve through our site. We reserve the right to disclose Non-Personal Information without restriction.

Disclosure to Affiliated Entities.  We reserve the right to provide your Personal Information to any affiliated entities we may have, including our subsidiaries.

Disclosure to Service Providers and Online Partners for Website Operations.  We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information to our trusted service providers that assist us with the operation and maintenance of this site.  For example, we may use third parties to process payments, host our servers, provide security, and provide production, fulfillment, optimization, analytics, and reporting services.  We will take commercially reasonable efforts to cause these third parties to agree to hold your information in confidence or to disclose information only to third parties that we believe in good faith are trustworthy regarding the confidentiality of your information.

Disclosure to Successors.   If we are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, or if we sell this website business or a line of business from this website, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal  Information as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.   In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors’ rights generally, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information to protect our rights or as required by law.

Disclosure Incident to Legal Process and Enforcement.  We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary (i) to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request (such as for example, to comply with a subpoena or court order), or (ii) to investigate or enforce violations of our rights or the security of this site.

For EU Customers, or Customers with operation activity within the EU, additional information on how we address GDPR Information Disclosure Regulations can be accessed within our [GDPR compliance FAQ](https://www.worketc.com/worketc-gdpr/#GDPRFAQ).

INFORMATION RELATED TO DATA COLLECTED THROUGH THE WORKetc SERVICE

WORKetc collects information under the direction of its Customers, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. WORKetcworks with its Customers to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We collect information for our Customers, if you are a customer of one of our Customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Customers that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

WORKetc may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Customers.

WORKetc has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the WORKetc’s Customer (the data controller). If the Customers requests COMPANY to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

WORKetc will retain personal data we process on behalf of Customers for as long as needed to provide services to our Customer. WORKetc will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

SPECIFIC INFORMATION ABOUT COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS

1st Party Cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies.  We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once.  Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

3rd Party Cookies for Web Analytics and Reporting.  We reserve the right to use web analytics services provided by 3rd parties. These services use 3rd party cookies (cookies passed by others, not by us) to collect Non-Personal Information about your use of this site.  These web analytics services may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on the service’s behalf.

Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personally identifiable information.

SOCIAL MEDIA

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

PUBLIC FORUMS

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at support@worketc.com.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

TESTIMONIALS

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. To request removal of your testimonial, contact us at support@worketc.com.

DATA SECURITY

We follow reasonable and appropriate industry standards to protect your Personal Information and data.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or method of data storage can be guaranteed 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your Personal Information by following generally accepted industry standards, we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information you transmit to us or archive at this site.

When you transmit Personal Information through our registration process or if you purchase products or services, we encrypt that information in transit using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

After the secure transfer of your Personal Information, the information is maintained and stored with 256-bit encryption.

ONWARD TRANSFER OUTSIDE YOUR COUNTRY OF RESIDENCE

Any Personal Information which we may collect on this site may be stored and processed within our Amazon Web Services infrastructure limited to locations in soley the EU, USA or AUSTRALIA.

UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will permit you to request or make changes or updates to your Personal Information for legitimate purposes.  Please email or write us using the contact information below under “Contact Us”. We request identification prior to approving such requests. We reserve the right to decline any requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require unreasonable time or effort of our technical or administrative personnel, or undermine the privacy rights of others.  We reserve the right to permit you to access your Personal Information in any account you establish with this site for purposes of making your own changes or updates, and in such case, instructions for making such changes or updates will be provided where necessary.

If you no longer desire our services, you can cancel your account by logging in and going to Settings -> Manage My Account to Cancel My Account.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@worketc.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

EMAIL; OPT-OUT

This site treats email messages and other electronic messages that are sent through this site and not viewable by others as confidential and private, except as required by law, including without limitation, the Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986, 18 U.S.C. Sections 2701-2711 (the “ECPA”).  The ECPA permits this site’s limited ability to intercept and/or disclose electronic messages, for example (i) as necessary to operate our system or to protect our rights or property, (ii) upon legal demand (court orders, warrants, subpoenas), or (iii) where we receive information inadvertently which appears to pertain to the commission of a crime.  This site is not considered a “secure communications medium” under the ECPA.

If you supply us with your e-mail address you may receive periodic messages from us with information specific to the site and required for the normal functioning of the site as well as for new products or services or upcoming events. If you prefer not to receive periodic email messages, you may opt-out by following the instructions on the email or by emailing us. Please see “Contact Us” below.

YOUR RIGHTS  
CONSENT: If you wish to subscribe to our marketing or any other communications, we will use your name and email address to send communications to you. Where applicable we will use best endeavor to inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we ever intend disclose your information to any third party for data processing we will make this known via the WORKetc list of [Data Sub Processors.](https://www.worketc.com/privacy_policy/gdpr/)  You may elect to stop receiving our marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in such emails.

We send push notifications from time to time in order to update you about any Customer Account Issues, Service updates, events and promotions we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these communications, simply elect to opt out.

ACCESS TO INFORMATION: You have the right to access information held about you.

RIGHT TO DELETION, CORRECTION AND RETRIEVAL We permit you to delete, correct and export information you have provided to us, subject to the conditions of our [Customer Service Agreement](https://www.worketc.com/service_agreement/) and the relevant Data Protection Laws (EU) as set out in our [GDPR Guidelines.](https://www.worketc.com/privacy_policy/gdpr/)

RETENTION. We retain Personal Data for as long as we provide the Services to you or your account remains open. However, we may keep some data after your account is closed or you cease using the Service, as required by law, audit compliance, regulatory requirements, security protocols where used to help prevent abuse or fraud, resolve disputes, enforce our Customer Terms, inform about WORKetc changes or updates you may be interested in or to fulfil future requests from you.  Where none of the above obligations no longer apply, your data will be securely destroyed within 12 months of your account being closed.

We may retain de-personalised/anonymized information after your account has been closed.

APPLICABLE DATA PROTECTION LAW  
For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679, the data controller is WORKetc Pty Ltd, a proprietary limited company registered in Australia with number 06418281 whose registered office is at Level 8, 99 Elizabeth St, SYDNEY NSW.  For more information on GDPR and how WORKetc addresses these regulations, [read here](https://www.worketc.com/privacy_policy/gdpr/).

EU CUSTOMERS / CUSTOMERS WITH EU OPERATIONS ONLY – WHERE WE STORE YOUR DATA  
By default, all Customer Data, from Customers located in the EU, is stored within the EU or UK via our service provider, Amazon Web Services.  From time to time, the Personal Data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Union and European Economic Zone. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EU who work for us or for one of partner providers. Such staff may be engaged in providing customer support services, or engaged in other related activities. When you accept the [Terms of Service](https://www.worketc.com/service_agreement/) and complete the action of submitting your Personal Data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing outside of the EU. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the guidelines set out by GDPR where applicable.

When your personal data is moved or accessed outside of the EU, we take all reasonable measures to help ensure your information is only transferred in full accordance with the GDPR applicable EU data protection law. Note that this will mean your information will only be transferred to a country that provides an adequate level of protection, currently being United States, United Kingdom or Australia or where WORKetc maintains operations and only where the recipient is bound by standard contractual clause according to conditions provided by the European Commission within its stated model clauses.

HOW WE MODIFY THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, and without prior notice, by posting an amended Privacy Policy that is always accessible by clicking on the “Privacy Policy” link on this site’s home page. Your continued use of this site indicates your acceptance of the amended Privacy Policy.  
You should check the Privacy Policy through this link periodically for modifications by clicking on the link provided near the top of the Privacy Policy for a listing of material modifications and their effective dates.

If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective.

CONTACT US

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact the owner and operator of this website business at:

Australia – Asia – Pacific – Rest of World  
WORKetc Pty Ltd  
Level 8, 99 Elizabeth St  
SYDNEY NSW 2000  
Email:  support@worketc.com  
Telephone: 1300 857 860  (aus)

USA – Canada  
WORKetc  
One Embarcadero Center  
Suite# 500,  
San Francisco, 94111  
Telephone:  (800) 322 7860 (usa)

UK & Europe  
WORKetc  
86-90 Paul Street,  
London EC2A 4NE  
United Kingdom  
Telephone: (0)20 3332 0860
